(Music plays)
Hey.
Oh, hello.
(Laughs)
Here I go.
Just your everyday humble
guardian of your most precious
letters and gifts.
(Music plays)
Delivering the mail
is my sacred duty.
Birthdays, anniversaries,
you name it, I deliver it.
Let me tell you.
The smiles on their faces
light up my day.
I love my job.
I really do.
Look at this house,
for instance.
That one.
The one that sits at the end
of this long, long road.
The one at the end of the cliff,
crumbling into the ocean.
You'd have to be
nuts to live there.
Wait wait wait.
Hold on.
Don't leave.
You know what?
This is actually not my story.
But it starts with the
delivery of a letter by me.
So I guess in a
way it is my story.
Ah, there they are, the twins.
Doctor, this patient
is missing a nose.
(Laughter)
Alfie, look!
He's looking great.
She! It's a snow lady
and our best one yet.
Hey, you little dung beetles!
Prepare for defeat!
(Shouts) Ah!
Whoa!
Dad, are you okay?
Never better.
(Shouting) Attack!
Two against one.
Take that!
Ha! Terrible shot sis!
Try this for size.
Oh!
Good shot.
Take this.
You missed.
What about that?
(Laughter)
Hey! Watch out!
(Car alarm goes off)
Oh.
That's a wonderful family.
Come on, you can do
better than that.
(Background chatter)
They are as happy
as happy can be.
(Laughter)
Enough!
Enough! Get off me!
(Laughing)
Not fair!
I surrender.
I surrender!
We won!
What are the three of you up to?
Come inside.
It's freezing.
I'll be right up.
You're in trouble now.
(Laughs)
Dad. Alfie!
Come on.
I'm coming.
Just getting the mail.
Sometimes letters
bring surprises.
Hey, I'm coming to get you.
(Music continues)
(Background chatter)
(Main titles)
Umm time for presents?
Very well.
What about dessert?
(Background laughter)
(Sliding noise)
It's just a little
something kids.
It's been a bit of a tough year.
This is great.
Did you make it yourself?
With my own fair hands.
Is this the ship you're
going to sail on?
Alfie! We promised
not to talk about that.
Sorry, mum.
I love it.
What is it?
It's a scarf.
Ah. It's beautiful.
Dad, it's your turn.
Open yours.
Oh, wow.
- I made the frame.
- And I did the painting.
I love it.
Your turn mum.
You got me a box?
(Laughing)
Turn the handle.
(Slow jingle plays)
(Shrieks)
Ahh!
(Laughing)
Hey, sis.
I've got a little
surprise for you, too.
(Shrieking)
Ah! Ughh!
Get back here.
You little dung beetle!
Ha!
(Background laughter)
(Background)
Take that!
(Laughter)
(Car horn beeps)
(Music continues)
(Background laughter)
(Car horn beeps)
(Plant pot breaks)
(Music continues)
(Squeaky noise)
Ah!
Ow.
(Laughter)
(Door slams)
(Footsteps)
(Door opens)
(Pumpkin splatters)
Hmm hmm hmm.
Oww.
(Laughter)
I spent ages on that.
It's pathetic.
Ah ha!
Blah.
Bleugh.
(Window shatters)
Ah!
Both of you in the house now!
Sorry, mum.
I didn't mean to.
This is your fault, Alfie.
No. It's yours.
I wish you two
would just behave.
She did it.
No, he did it.
I don't want to hear it.
Get inside and tidy your room.
Now!
What about the Christmas tree?
Dad would never leave it
this late to decorate.
Well, father isn't
here anymore, is he?
Elise!
If he was,
he would not be impressed
with the way
you two have been acting.
Neither of you help
around the house.
Your room is a mess and you
don't appreciate anything.
Appreciate what?
We live in this ramshackled
house in the middle of nowhere.
We have nothing.
All Alfie does is whine,
and all you do is yell at us.
I'm not sure this family
even deserves a Christmas.
I hate this place.
And I hate you.
I hope you don't mean that.
Oh.
I don't know how much longer
I can do this on my own.
Mm.
(Loud background noises)
(Sighs)
I miss dad.
Yes. Direct hit.
Ha! Ew!
Yuck! Elise!
(Laughter)
Ah, you little dung beetle!
Take that!
Ha!
I wasn't aiming at you.
I was aiming at the clock.
Ah! Elise, we need to tidy up.
Ah!
Ah! Ah!
You missed again.
Did I really?
You're just a terrible climber.
Ah! Stop it!
Come on.
Mum's gonna get really upset.
She's always upset.
Hmm. Where did it go?
Ah!
Ha! Finders keepers.
Oh, look at this mess.
It's like a tower of chaos.
Ah!
Hmm. You better clean that up.
Mum will be here soon.
I just wish she wasn't
so angry all the time.
That's wishing for
the impossible.
You know, she hasn't been
the same since dad left.
Neither have you.
Well, you can talk.
He'll come back.
I know it.
I wish we weren't in
this dreary old house.
What if we could have
all the wishes we wanted?
I'd wish myself away from this
place and away from everybody
Telling me what to
do all the time.
You think you can do
anything you want? No rules.
I just wish we could
have an adventure.
Twelve year-olds don't
have adventures.
I just wish dad was home.
Ow! Ow!
Ow!
Sorry, mum.
We'll tidy up.
Elise, help your brother.
I wish I could have
Christmas somewhere else.
Be careful what you wish for.
Elise. Be nice.
Here. I have a little
something for the two of you.
Your dad left it in
case of an emergency.
What is it?
Open it and see.
Huh?
A watch?
It doesn't even tick.
Why would dad leave
us this old thing?
This is no ordinary watch.
It's a wish watch.
A wish watch?
What?
According to your father,
this used to belong
to The Wish Collector.
He can hear all the children
in the world making wishes.
Then late one night, he appears
and whisks you
to The Land of Sometimes.
Where all your wishes come true.
- Wow.
- But not the way you'd expect.
How did dad get it?
I don't know exactly, but it
was on one of his
many adventures.
He used to tell me tales of
a mysterious island where all
four seasons pass
in just one day.
So, wait, are you saying that
We can make wishes
with this watch?
Maybe. But every time you
do, I want you to think,
What would your father wish for?
I miss dad.
Me too.
But as long as we stick
together, we'll be okay.
I just really need the
two of you to help me.
It's not the same without him.
I know.
Now come on.
Bed, the pair of you.
(Song begins)
Close your eyes and make a wish.
Make a little dream come true.
See what happens if you do.
You can make a wish come true.
Sweet dreams.
I wish we could go
on an adventure.
Do you think there
is a Wish Collector?
No. Don't be daft.
I'm going to sleep.
(Singing)
You can make a wish come true.
(Clock chimes and
song starts)
Close your eyes and make a wish.
Make a little dream come true.
See what happens if you do.
You can make a wish come true.
Come on dare make a wish.
Do not be afraid of this.
You can do what you want to do.
You can reach for the stars.
See the angel that you are.
Go on dare make a wish.
And you,
Ah, what's happening?
What's going on?
Can make your wish come true.
Find a secret in a shell. Hear
the tune of a wishing well.
Find a slide that never ends.
Find a pirate for a friend.
Step inside the Milky Way.
Alfie, look!
A ship!
Elise, get away from the window!
It's heading straight for us.
You can wish it any way.
Come on dare make a wish.
Do not be afraid of this.
You can do what you want to do.
You can reach for the stars.
See the angel that you are.
Go on dare make a wish.
And you will make
your wish come true.
(Coughing)
I've gotta work on my entrances.
That mist gets right
to your chest.
Ah, well.
Ah, there you are.
I was wondering where
you'd gotten to.
I felt like I'd been trapped on
that island for an
absolute eternity.
Hey, you!
That's my watch.
Our watch.
What are you doing in our room?
Uh, well. Hello. I didn't see
you lurking there.
You must be.
Elise. And that's
my brother, Alfie.
Elise! Alfie!
Get up!
And who exactly are you?
Well, you should know.
You did call me after all.
In Denmark, they call me
ønskesamler.
In France,
Le collectionneur de souhaits.
And in Japan,
U~isshukorekut
At least, I think
that's how they say it.
But here I'm simply known
as The Wish Collector.
The Wish Collector?
Ah, you've heard of me?
Well, I suppose I am
a bit of a celebrity.
World famous, household name.
Well, at least I used to be.
Mum told us about you, but...
But she tells us a load
of things that aren't true.
Well, here I am, am I not?
So few seem to know
about me nowadays.
But at least children
still make wishes.
Excuse me.
Hold me up.
I want to see the view.
The wish watch... it talks?
Oh, yes. Quite opinionated
as a matter of fact.
Mind it, will you?
Often the hardest trick
is getting him to shut up.
How frightful!
Huh? Rude.
Well, I like him.
This chill is freezing my cogs.
Here. That should
keep you quiet.
Boy that tickles.
I'm delighted to say I have
come to take you to The Land of
Sometimes, where all
your wishes come true.
Our wishes?
Fantabulous wishes.
Wait. Um.
Which one of you is the eldest?
Me? Hey, only by three minutes.
Well, you get to hold the
watch first then. My watch.
Our watch.
Whatever. So you can make
any of our wishes come true.
Of course.
As long as you're
holding the wish watch.
But we don't want to do it in
a stuffy old room like this.
No, no.
Stuffy old rooms mean
stuffy old wishes.
No, no, no.
We need somewhere
adventureumptuous!
Exciting!
Wait. I'm not going anywhere.
And magnifique!
Then I'll go myself.
You will not. Watch me.
Hold on.
You're not afraid
are you, Alfie?
(Shrieks)
He's afraid of his own shadow.
Let's just leave the
little dung beetle here.
You can't go Elise.
Of course I can.
Who's gonna stop me?
Well, I made all the
arrangements for two.
But if you must stay, Alfie.
Come on, let's go.
Very well.
It looks like
there's just one adventurer.
(Song starts)
Come on
Let's make our
first wish already.
Elise.
(Singing) It's a dream, but
we're wide awake.
This is real.
But I think it's fake.
I can see that I'm still asleep.
I can fly. But I'm in the deep.
But I'm in the deep.
It's forever
But won't last long.
I'm awake, but I could be wrong.
There is a light, but
my eyes are closed.
Yes. It's stranger
than you suppose.
Stranger than you can suppose.
But that's how it always goes.
How it always goes.
This is no ordinary journey.
To the shops or to your school.
It's an odyssey intended
to be awe inspiring, splendid.
A voyage is the jewel.
Oh, I don't like
the look of this.
I wonder why do they call
it the land of sometimes?
Because sometimes it's there
and sometimes it's not!
This is The Land of Sometimes.
The land of now and then.
The now is always with us.
And then comes back again.
It's forever but won't last
long.
I'm awake, but I could be wrong.
There's a light, but
my eyes are closed.
Yes. It's stranger
than you suppose.
Welcome to The
Land of Sometimes.
Where all four seasons
pass in one day.
It's just how I imagined it!
This is The Land of Sometimes.
The land of now and then.
The now is always with us.
And then comes back again.
Where wishes and
adventure are combined
And slowly turned, into life
itself,
And lessons that
cannot be unlearned.
Oh wait, I almost
forgot the rules.
I knew there'd be a catch.
It's just a few teeny weeny
details barely worth mentioning.
No? Go ahead, mention it.
Being a magical island each day
at the end of winter, The Land
of Sometimes sinks and
crumbles into the ocean.
And we all drown?!
No, of course not!
You just become a permanent
resident on the island.
What?! Turn the ship around now!
Oh, come now.
As long as you complete your
wishes before winter ends,
you'll be fine and dandy.
Complete our wishes?
Of course.
The wish watch has
granted you six wishes.
Six wishes?
Whoever's holding the
watch can make the wish.
But just be careful
what you wish for.
We have three wishes each.
Indeed.
Just be sure to have used all
your wishes and be back to the
ship before winter ends.
Oh, I don't like
the sound of this.
Ah. Perfect timing.
Spring is in the air.
All docked.
Come on.
This is The Land of Sometimes.
(Song ends)
Let's go! Mind it, will you?
Ohh...(Laughter)
Slow down.
We need to stick together.
Come on, let's make
our first wish already.
(Flying object thuds)
Oww! Alfie.
It wasn't me.
Look out!
Ouch!
What's this?
Ah! Now that is a giggle nut.
They love to be thrown.
(Giggle noises)
Oh, it's so cute.
Well, it stings when it hits
you on the back of the head.
Who threw it?!
(Giggling)
I think you may have found one
of the island's many residents.
This particular one loves
a good giggle nut fight.
But the Lad is a bit of a loner.
You know the type?
Yeah, I sure do.
I think he might have taken
a shine to you, Elise.
Funny way of showing it.
Come out and fight!
(Throws gigglenut)
(Laughter)
(Background)
Wooo!
(Giggling)
She's not a very
good thrower, is she?
Baa baa. Chickenn!
You little dung beetle.
Take that.
(Metal clanking sound)
Yes! Direct hit!
Uh oh.
That's not The Lad.
What is it?
Oh! Oh!
(Sinister music plays)
(Mechanical whirring)
Who dares throw gigglenuts
at me?!
Guardian, we have no quarrel
with you. The Lad
Threw it at her. She was just
throwing it back.
How dare you bring more
children to this island?!
After all you've done.
If you must know,
they called to me.
So, they have the watch.
What? Um. No.
Now, you mention it. As my good
pal Socrates once said...
The true wisdom...
Hand over the watch,
you little brat!
Look out!
(Screaming) Ahh! Run!
Oh!
(Screaming) Ahhh!
Don't trust anything this
so called Wish Collector says
Let go!
He's a trickster.
If you give me the watch, I'll
give you anything you want.
Why should we trust you?
Give me that watch.
Whoaa.
Oi, you're jumbling me up.
Give it to me now!
Ah!
Help!
No!
Oof!
Oh. Me coccyx...
Gimme gimme gimme!
Get off!
Let go!
This is our dad's!
Ugh, I wish you were
up that mountain.
(Ding)
Wish granted.
What have you done?
Ahhh, you inpertinent little
shi...
(Flying off into the distance)
(Thud)
Ah!
(Mechanical thuds)
(Machine shuts down)
Ah! Hmm.
I'm not sure that
was such a good idea.
I didn't mean to.
Who was that?!
Well, that was The Guardian.
He controls the volcano, and
he's desperate to get his hands
on the wish watch.
So he can use the
wishes for himself.
Mhm. Well, something like that.
But it looks like Elise sent
him back to where he belongs.
Huh?
(Thunder and lighting strikes)
Ah. There you are.
(Whispering) Must have
seen me leave the island.
Doesn't normally venture down
this far.
What do you think
was going to happen?
Hopefully we won't be seeing
him again anytime soon.
Ooh. What's that?
Does she always
run off like that?
Always.
As my good friend Confucius used
to say, it doesn't matter
how slow you go,
as long as you don't stop.
Sounds like you
need some breakfast.
Actually, I am hungry.
(Stomach growls)
Well, go ahead, it's your turn.
Why don't you make a wish?
I'm sure the wish watch can
summon up a scrum diddly feast.
Oh. I might like one of those.
Go on Alfie
Shouldn't I check
with Elise first?
Oh, I'm sure she's famished too.
Besides, it's her turn next.
Okay? I wish for a fantastic
and marvellous feast!
(Ding) Wish granted
(Music)
Wow Alfie!
Look!
It worked!
What worked?
My first wish. I wished
for a magnificent feast.
And there it is.
Within seconds it appeared.
You made another wish already!
I thought you'd be hungry.
I mean, I'm famished.
We haven't had any breakfast.
Besides, you get the next wish.
What is this disgusting stuff?
This is completely undesirable
and inedible. We can't eat this.
Well, of course you can.
In fact, some of this is very
rare. From the five corners of
the world.
Five corners?
Mhmm, remarkably delicious.
Ooh. Tingle berry pie!
You will love these.
Tingle berry pie?
Ooh! And slime gurgle cake.
They make your tongue tingle.
Ow. (Shrieks)
(Loud burps)
Well done Alfie. This really is
a magnificent feast.
Ooh! My favourite!
(Trumpet sound)
(Laughing)
Ha! Toot berries
(Trumpet sounds)
Gross.
(Laughing)
Do you get it? Hahaha
They make you toot!
(Trumpet sounds)
Ha! This is amazing.
Elise, you have to try it!
Er, no, thank you very much.
(Trumpet sounds)
So immature.
Er,
I am hungry.
That looks edible.
Hmm. That smells edible.
Hey!
Woohoo!
(Fliggle noises)
Hey, you! Give it back!
That's mine.
(Fliggle noises)
Wooo
(Fliggle noises continue)
Weehoo!
That was the only
thing worth eating.
Give it back.
(Fliggle noises)
Uh oh...
Hey, that's not your...
Would you get off my face?
Oh, there you are.
Ugh, finally!
(Puppy dog noises)
Fine here.
(Swallow and loud burp)
You're welcome.
Now get off.
Go on! Away with you!
(Puppy dog noises)
You won't get rid
of him that easily.
You just fed a Fliggle.
Did you just say Fliggle?
Once you feed a Fliggle, they're
attached to you for good.
You'll have a friend for life.
I don't want a friend.
Especially not one
that steals my food.
Go on. Shoo!
(Gurggling sounds)
Huh? Fliggle?
What's going on?
Ohhhh.
I've got visitors!
Slingy!
Slingy?! Bleugh
No wonder all this
food looks disgusting.
I didn't realise
it was slug food.
Elise. Don't be rude.
And you!
(Fliggle noises)
Oh, mama!
Oh, please.
(Song starts)
Please come in, come in.
Take off your shoes.
Sorry. The floor is always wet.
(Singing)
Hello there!
I am the River Slouch Sling.
A scaly and wobbly
Oh slimy old thing.
I'm squelchy and orange,
with bright beady eyes.
But don't worry. Not scary.
I'm ratherly shy.
I four legs and one snout.
And a rubbery tail.
And a very large tum that
is covered in scales.
Ooh!
My home is a shell that I dug
up myself full of weeds, sugar
jars and old socks on the shelf.
Ooh. I have BuzzyBazzoos
for my supperly feast.
I'm a dear, a peculiar,
muddy old beast.
When my bright beady eyes catch
a succulent Sniggle. I dive
And I swallow, a
burp and a giggle.
Take it away
Musical Molluscs!
Oh. Sounds good.
(Music continues)
(Bubble pops)
Help!
(Music continues)
(Singing)
Oh, yes!
He's squelchy and quite
dear in his ways.
It's so fun to make friends.
It's a marvellous day.
He's got scales, he's got swing.
And he's slithery too!
He's the River Slouch Sling.
Do we like him?
We do!
(Audience clapping)
Thank you.
Stop, stop! Don't. Stop.
Don't stop!
You horrible slug!
Elise!
Disgusting.
I hate this place.
(Thunder strikes)
Ow! Ow!
The Guardian! Looks like
someone's annoyed him.
Which one of you did it?
Wait. Why are you
afraid of The Guardian?
I thought he just
wanted the wish wash.
He does, but he controls that
volcano.
He could send honeycomb lava
down over us whenever he wanted.
You need to avoid him.
Horrible beast!
He should never have
come to this island.
So glad he's not mad at me.
Good luck kids!
(Screaming)
Ahh!
What's he talking about?
Oh, don't listen to him.
Always a bit of a worrier.
Exaggerates tremendously.
Well, that was a
complete waste of a wish.
My turn.
Oi! That tickles.
Huh? See if you and your
friend can do any better.
I can wish for anything.
Of course, but I would just
try and be a little clearer.
The wish watch can interpret
whatever you say
however he wants.
Oi, get off!
Hey! Come back!
You. You've got the watch.
(Boing noises)
(Laughter)
(Donkey noises)
(Boing noises continue)
(Crazy laughter)
(Donkey noises continue)
(Boing noises continue)
Ooh SpringDoncs.
They're a rare sight indeed.
SpringDoncs?
(Crazy laughter)
That's a funny name.
Looks like summer's on its way.
I think that one must
have a wonky spring.
(Enchanting music and
fluttering begins)
(Fairies whispering)
Follow us. Follow us.
Off she goes again.
(Fairies whispering)
Follow us
Help!
Fun! Excitement! Wish!
Get off!
You're jumbling me up.
Help! That tickles!
Hey! That's not yours!
Give it back!
Let go of my hands!
Fun. Excitement.
Wish, wish. Wish Watch.
I know my next wish.
I wish for excitement
and no more rules!
(Ding)
Wish granted.
Oh.
(Music grows)
When did it become summer?
Did I miss something?
Oh isn't it just perfect?
Follow us.
Oh no.
A mediocris.
What's that?
A fairy.
Really? A fairy?
That's amazing!
I take it you've
never met a fairy?
Well, no.
Most are troublesome, but this
one is the embodiment of chaos.
If there's one thing I've
learned in my many journeys,
It's always avoid fairies.
Even the nice ones take
little kiddies teeth you know.
You mean tooth fairies?
Exactly.
Ahh!
(Gulp sound)
Disgusting.
Oh, blimey.
They're real!
Let's just hope we've caught
this one on a good day.
Elise, wait for us!
Follow us.
Ugh, that sister of mine.
She never listens.
Perhaps she's deaf.
Has her hearing been tested
by a good otologist?
I know a marvellous
chap in Krakow.
Elise, wait.
(Fairies whispering)
Follow us
Follow us.
Hello? Is anybody here?
Well.
Huh?
What have we got here?
Well.
Oooo. Eugh.
What are you wearing?
Oh, my. Eugh.
Have you looked in the mirror?!
We can't have this, can we?
Mediocrisae! Pixies!
Fairies!
We have an emergency!
This is where the fun begins.
(Song starts)
Weehoo!
(Singing) You're about
to learn that nothing
is the way you thought it was.
That dark is light.
That dull is bright.
That big is small. Because
all logic is unreasonable.
No dreary law applies. No need
for things to stay the same.
No rules for shape or size.
Instead of boring constancy.
A change at every turn.
The everyday mundane
routine, no longer your concern.
A cavalcade of mystery, a
paradox of joy. Enthralling for
a girl like you.
And I suppose, a boy.
Elise. What have
they done to you?
(Fairies sing)
We all could use a makeover
A change sure beats the rest.
An imagination takeover.
Be crazy. Self-possessed!
Look closely for the unforeseen.
Change is king
and change is queen.
Break the rules is what I mean.
It's a never ending quest.
(Music continues)
Woo hoo!
Young man, please explain
yourself.
And though I hate to moan,
you ought to know
This tower is a fairy-only zone!
Elise! Elise!
It's gone too far.
We're out of here. And fast.
Oh, please don't go.
We've just begun.
It's gonna be a blast!
Woo hoo!
It's crazy.
You should want to leave
just when the fun gets hot.
Too late.
Get off!
He needs me now.
And I am all he's got.
Not anymore.
(Banging on door)
Elise! Let me in, Elise!
Alfie. No no no.
No.
No no no no no no.
You can't leave now.
We've only just begun.
What are you worried
about him for?
He's just a very big cry baby.
Leave my brother out of this.
What's wrong with you?
This is exciting!
Isn't that what
you wished for?
Why would you ever
want to leave?
You can do anything you want.
No rules!
Get off me!
No!
(Fliggle noise)
Quick! Run!
Rude! Little girl!
Ugh!
(Fliggle noises)
Ow!
Stay off my tower!
(Shouting)
Ahh!
Whoa!
(Thuds)
Ahh!
Elise, you're so selfish.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean for
it to go that far.
I just wished for excitement.
You need to grow up. Not
everything in life is exciting.
Give me the watch.
It's my turn to make a wish now.
Like your so called feast.
Well, better than a
selfish wish like yours.
I wish you'd just shut
up and stop whining.
Ooh. Careful. I wouldn't
do that if I were...
Well, I wish you would just
think about others for a change.
I wish you would just grow up
and stop being such a baby.
I really would be careful.
Well, I just wish you'd go
away and leave me alone.
(Ding)
Wish granted.
(Shouting)
Woah!
What did you do?!
I didn't mean to.
Whoa, whoa.
(Background shouting)
(Mechanical thud)
(Magical explosion)
(Shouting)
Ahh!
Oh bother. Well, I did try
to warn them.
Excuse me.
Ah, there you are.
Don't get too attached
to this bunch.
As Confucius once said,
roads were made for
journeys, not destinations.
You are such an old softie.
They have a lot to learn
And now they have no wish watch
to help them.
All going according
to plan, I would say.
(Loud thud) (Coughing)
Woah.
Elise! What did I do?
(Strange bird cooing)
(Falling through trees)
Ahh!
Oh.
Thanks, Fligs.
(Fliggle noises)
(Thud)
Ow!
Ugh, that little dung beetle!
I can't believe he did that.
Now, where are we?
Elise?
Elise! Elise!
Oh! Skunks.
(Strange bird noise)
Huh?
Hello.
Hello?
Who's there?
Ooh, a child.
Are you here for the tour?
Tour? No, I'm here
to find my sister.
Well, maybe she's inside.
What does she look like?
Uh, a bit like me, but a girl.
Obviously. We're twins.
Ooh.
Fancy. Never met twins before.
I can let you in and you
can have a look around.
Well, I guess there's no
point going backwards.
Just knock.
(Knocking)
(Door opens)
Good luck.
Good luck? With what?
(Door shuts)
(Laughter)
Elise!
(Door handles swinging)
Ah!
(Strange creature noise)
What? This is ridiculous.
(Banging on doors)
Ahh!
Where's the end?
There isn't one.
You need to choose a door.
I beg your pardon?
- He's right, you know.
- Huh?
Pick me.
I'm sure there are all
kind of treats behind me.
Don't listen to him.
If you want to get out of here,
then you need to go through me.
I've been trying the doors.
Well, you haven't tried me.
Or me.
Very well.
(Laughter)
Will you look at that?
I thought you said you
could get me out of here.
I'm just a door.
I don't know where I lead.
Maybe you need to try another.
This is ridiculous.
Sorry I got you into this Fligs.
I never pay attention
to what's right in front of me.
And now look at us.
Stuck in the middle of
somewhere.
I wish Mother was here.
(Fliggle noises)
Mother, you know, the person
who takes care of you.
A person like me,
but much bigger.
Tucks you in at night. Makes you
feel safe and not alone.
She would sing us a
lullaby when we get scared.
I don't think anyone
ever sang to her.
How did it go?
(Song starts) Close your eyes
and make a wish
Make a little dream come true.
Close your eyes and make a wish.
See what happens if you do.
You can make a wish come true.
(Song continues)
Come on dare make a wish.
Do not be afraid of this.
You can do what you want to do.
You can reach for the stars.
See the angel that you are.
Go on dare make a wish.
And you will make your wish
come true.
(Together)
I miss home.
(Fliggle noises)
(Bright light turns on)
There's a light.
It may be a way out!
(Fliggle noises)
(Gigglenut thud)
Fliggle?!
I wouldn't go that way miss.
Ughh!
Ouch!
Not safe if you ask me.
Well, I'm not asking you, am I?
(Giggling)
Ow!
I'm just trying to help.
(Fliggle noises)
(Gigglenut thud)
Well, you're not helping.
Go away and stop throwing
those silly nuts.
(Gigglenut flies)
I didn't know The
Guardian was behind me.
I was just trying to
have a bit of fun.
(Gigglenut flies)
Is that the best you can do?
(Gigglenut flies in slow motion)
(Thud)
Oh, will you stop it?
I don't have time for this.
I need to find my brother.
Wait, wait, young lad.
Looks a bit like you.
Oh, yeah.
I know where he is.
You do?
Yeah. He's just over this
really massive wall.
Yeah, right.
And how exactly am I
supposed to get over there?
Stop wasting my time.
No, wait wait, wait.
No, I can help.
I don't need any
help from anybody.
Come on Fligs!
(Fliggle noises)
If you say so.
(Gigglenut noise)
- Hello.
- Huhh?
Goodbye
(Giggling noises)
He can fly?!
Wait!
Why didn't he say he could fly?
Silly green head nut slinger.
Looks like we have no choice.
Come on.
It's okay.
How could it get any worse?
(Music grows)
(Mechanical whirring)
(Strange bird noises)
(Blowing raspberries)
(Strange elephant noises)
(Laughter)
I don't suppose you know
the way out of here.
(Strange bird noise)
(Panting and footsteps)
(Shrieks)
Ah!
(Music intensifies)
A wishing well.
Mum?
Dad?!
Sorry, Alfie, but your coin
could really help both of us.
I wish Alfie and I could go home
and be a family again.
I hope it works.
(Slime bubbling)
Ah! Watch out Fliggle!
(Bubble pops)
(Song starts)
What is that thing?
I'm Mrs Blip and I'm slippery.
I slip and I slide.
I live in a bucket
with bubbles and slime.
I hide in banana skins.
I hide in the tip.
And my favourite thing to do
is make people slip! Ha ha!
Who is throwing
things down my well?
Sorry, I was just making a wish.
Making a wish!
It is a wishing well.
This is a memory well,
not a wishing well. (Music)
There are no wishes here.
Horrible rude child.
I'm just trying to find
my brother
and that tricky Wish Collector.
The Wish Collector?
A troublemaker. Always
promising fantabulous wishes
with his wish watch.
Well, yes.
That's how I got here.
Ah. Perfect. Oh!
Ha ha!
(Slime explodes)
Heads up!
Have a nice trip.
Ha ha!
(Singing)
I'm tripping you up!
(Screaming)
Ahh! Woah!
(Door slams shut)
(Strange bird noises)
Look. It's another one.
Shh.
He'll hear you.
Oooh.
(Doors slamming)
(Windows opening)
Quick, everyone!
The mouse is in the maze!
He's already got a head start!
Why does he look so confused?
What is this place?
It's all fake!
Hey! Who are you calling fake?
He's just like all the kids
that get trapped in here, rude!
Stop it!
I need to find a
way out of here.
Can you help me, please?
And why should we help you?
We haven't had this much
fun in years!
Not since the last contender.
(Balloon pop)
Waaaah!
(Laughter)
I hope he can run.
Hey, kid.
Over here! Over here!
Let's see if he gets it.
Nobody gets it.
Another dead end.
Faster kid. We're getting bored!
Oh, he's getting close!
No, you can't go in there!
I told you.
He's running in circles.
(Laughter)
They all run in circles!
I told you!
Non, non, non!
Absolument pas!
Oo he's climbing!
That's cheating!
Hey, wait!
(Laughter)
You aren't supposed to do that!
Hey!
Stop it!
That tickles!
Stop him!
Ow!
My nose!
My eyebrows!
Stop it!
No!
(Background shouting)
No! No!
(Background shouting continues)
(Window slides open)
(Strange bird calls)
Whoa!
Wooo!
Waaah!
(Sigh)
(Background laughter)
Right, you little brat!
Give me the wish watch
and I may let you go.
(Fliggle noises)
Bleugh!
You disgusting little beast!
Leave him alone!
Can't you see he's frightened?
Ha ha ha!
And so you should be,
you horrible, rude child.
I just want to find my brother
and get off this island.
I tell you what.
You give me the wish watch
and I may let you out.
I don't have it.
Liar!
I'm not lying.
But you said that's
how you got here.
Yes, but my brother wished me
far away and I ended up here.
Even her brother
doesn't like her.
(Fliggle noises)
(Hissing)
No, he was just angry.
I don't blame him.
Mhmm. So your brother
has the watch, does he?
(Screaming)
Whoa! Whoa!
Help! Help! Help!
(Sheep bleating)
(Flings through the air)
Baa!
Whoa!
(Sheep bleating)
Woah! Woah!
Hey, that was kind of fun.
Thanks, Lamby. Here.
It's my last one.
Any chance you could
give me a lift?
If I can get to that giant tree
over there,
Maybe I can spot Elise.
(Sheep bleating)
Baa
(Fliggle noises)
(Metal cage swinging)
The keys!
Can you get them?
(Fliggle noises)
(Swinging continues)
Come on.
You can do it.
Now!
(Keys jangling)
(Loud thud)
We make a good team.
Come on, let's get out of here.
You could have gotten
out all this time?!
You're suggesting we lead
the boy to The Guardian?
But we hate The Guardian.
And he hates us.
Those brats have
really annoyed him.
He could pour honeycomb lava
into all of your lovely sewers.
You have a point.
Besides, maybe he'll give
us a wish of our own.
We deserve it more than
those spoilt little monsters.
Okay, so what is the plan then?
I'll lead the boy up the
volcano,
Where The Guardian can deal
with him!
Did you hear that?
They're gonna lead
Alfie to The Guardian.
We need to find him.
(Door opens)
(Mechanical whirring)
(Fliggle shrieking)
(Slime gurggling)
(Slurping)
Hmm.
Aha!
I knew I heard something!
Get back here!
Ah! Ah!
(Slime exploding)
(Slime exploding continues)
Ha ha! Hahaha!
(Screaming)
Arghhh!
Ahh!
(Toilet flush sound)
(Screaming continues)
Ha ha ha!
(Slime flushing)
Mhmm.
(Slime rushing)
(Screaming continues)
Ha ha! Ha ha!
(Slow motion)
Nooo!
(Screaming)
Ahhh!
Get back here, you
horrible little creatures!
(Fliggle noises)
(Loud thud)
(Screaming)
We did it!
Give me five. Or twenty!
(Sheep bleating)
Woah. Woah.
(Squelching sounds)
Ugh
(Bird caws)
Aghh!
(Squelching sounds continue)
Ugh. Ugh.
Wow! Look at that.
That took you a long time!
How did you...
Tea's almost cold.
Tea! There's no time for tea.
We need to find Elise!
You haven't found her yet?
I thought that's what you've
been busy doing all this time.
Give me the watch.
I need to make a wish
and find Elise.
Be careful Alfie. You only
have one wish left.
And officially,
it's Elise's turn.
What do you mean, one wish left?
We've only had four.
The Guardian, the feast,
that horrible fairy.
And then the last one.
But that was an accident.
Don't forget Elise's first wish.
What first wish?
In your bedroom.
The wish to go on an adventure.
That counted?!
(Slurping sounds)
Ugh, she must have been
holding the watch.
(Slurping continues)
So we only have one wish left?!
I'm afraid so.
And remember, the island
crumbles at the end of winter.
We have to find her
and get out of here.
Oh. I can help you with that.
Does everything in
this place talk?
Now the tree is talking!
Excuse me!
Woah! Mr Smaller.
I am no tree, sir.
Mr Smaller.
I wish you would stop creeping
up on people like that.
Mr... Smaller?
Mr Smaller than smaller than
small. If you must know.
Always skulking in the shadows
and flying around on his
robotic butter moth.
If you're looking for
a young girl,
I bumped into one not
too far from here
Looking for her brother.
She was convinced he had been
abducted by that Guardian.
She's heading up the
volcano to find him.
Elise. We need to go. Now!
It's too dangerous, Alfie.
All the more reason
we need to find her.
Oh, I'd be quick if I were you.
She's probably
halfway up already.
Wish Collector. I need
another wish. Please.
This is your last
wish, young Alfie.
Better make it count.
I wish Elise was safe and at
the bottom of the volcano!
(Ding)
(Strange bird cawing)
What was that?
Autumn? We need to hurry!
Only one more season to go.
Well, that's odd.
What happened?
It didn't work.
Are you sure she went up
the volcano?
Of course. Are you
suggesting I'm a liar?
How dare you!
No. Well, not really.
It's just that the wish watch
only does that when a wish
isn't possible or
a rule is broken.
I saw her with my own eyes!
And if you aren't quick, that
Guardian will catch her and
drop her in his honeycomb lava.
You're all frightened of this
Guardian. But I'm not.
And I won't let
him get my sister.
Now you're either with
me or I'll go on my own.
Well, aren't you becoming
a brave little chap.
The volcano's just there. We're
right at the bottom of it.
But how do we get
over this wall?
(Humming and singing)
Mhm mhm mhm mhm mhm.
(Giggling sound)
Woah! You...
Need some throwing lessons.
(Giggling sound)
Ugh! You missed!
Take that!
(Laughing)
Woo!
Ah. Two against one.
Ow. Hey, not fair!
(Gigglenut thud)
Ow. Aah! Help help!
Perfect shot! Alfie
would be proud.
Ahh! Ahh!
Help miss! Please.
Oh, all the blood's rushing
from my feet to my head.
Give us a hand, please.
(Fliggle noises)
Well, I suppose if
he promises to help us,
Maybe we can help him.
Anything! Anything! Miss. You
name it. I am at your service.
Just, just help me down, please.
(Fliggle noises)
Oh, hello.
Oh, no. No! Get off!
Get off! (Laughing)
Wooo!
So, you'll do
anything to help me?
Did I say that, miss?
I don't recall.
Of course, of course.
I'm just kidding.
Well, we need a lift up to
the top of that volcano.
(Laughing)
Volcano?
You're serious?
Why would you want
to go up there?
Well, you've seen The Guardian.
He's a mechanical beast.
He would crush
you in an instant.
My brother's in danger.
He's being led into a trap.
But, miss, look, I can't.
Figured you'd chicken out.
(Fliggle clucks)
Hey, don't you start.
Okay, I'll tell you what.
I'll take you as far as I can.
You will?
But I need you to promise.
You can't tell that monster
of a Guardian I helped you.
Okay, I promise.
Right. Let's go!
Come on Fligs, hurry up!
Woo hoo!
Ha ha woo!
Woo hoo! Weee!
(Laughing)
What about you?
Most of us Islanders
were kids like you.
Brought to the island
by The Wish Collector.
Some made their wishes
and left, and others,
Well, we didn't have
a lot to go back to.
Weehoo!
(Water splashes)
And what about The Guardian?
Why does he want the
watch so desperately?
Oh, he had a family and wanted
desperately to go home, too.
But he didn't make it
off the island in time.
He's always blamed
The Wish Collector.
Thinks he still has a wish left.
So you're saying he's been
trapped as a beast all this time
Poor thing.
(Screaming in the distance)
Woahh!
Weee!
I'd rather walk if it's all the
same to you.
(Music continues)
(Gust of winds and thunder)
Woah!
(Thunder and lighting)
Weehoo!
(Music intensifies)
(Background thunder)
Woah!
Ahh!
Be careful.
Sorry miss! Winter's coming,
but it's not here yet.
Ha ha ha! Woo!
You're amazing!
Well I don't know about that.
(Thunder strikes)
Ah! That was way too close.
What's that noise?
(Thunder and lighting continues)
Winter's coming.
Shut me down here!
I can get you a little closer!
A little more!
Winter's here already!
We've got to hurry.
Ah! Watch out!
The path! It's gone.
The clouds are moving faster.
We're running out of time.
Woah! Woah!
(Wind blowing)
The snow's too much. We need to
turn back. It's too dangerous.
Quick! In here!
We can't stop. We need
to find Elise.
Maybe we can try
the watch again.
Just be careful
what you wish for.
Okay. Here goes.
Mhmm.
Oh wishy. Look at your poor cogs
Oh skunks.
It's frozen.
(Fliggle noises)
I'll miss you Fligs.
Keep him safe!
Ahh! Woah, what are you doing?
Take care of Fliggle.
(Falling)
Ahhh! Elise!
Oh, it's as cold as
a burgundy snail.
Look, it's the Buttermoth!
Mr Smaller must have sent it
to help us.
Well, I never.
Who'd have thought?
(Ice breaks)
Ahhh!
(Shouting)
Help!
Elise!
Elise, is that you?
(Background shouting)
Help me!
I'm coming.
Alfie! Be careful.
Alfie!
Help!
Elise! Where are you?
Help! Help!
Help!
Over there!
I'm coming!
Elise!
Help!
(Rock cracking)
Ahh!
(Music intensifies)
Alfie!
Careful Alfie!
Hold on!
You have to let go!
Grab my hand!
I've got you.
I can't.
Trust me. You can do it.
You're jumbling me up!
You did it!
Yeah...
Well, I never.
Let's go somewhere
else next time.
You had to wish for adventure.
You couldn't have
wished for a puppy.
You know how much
work a puppy is.
You have to feed it. You have to
walk it. You have to pick up its
I missed you too, sis.
(Mechanical whirring)
Behind you! Look out!
Ha! Welcome to my
electric volcano!
Hand over the wish watch or
I drop him.
This isn't meant for you!
You had your chance!
This is all your fault.
All of it!
Let him go!
Eight-legged metal monster!
Winter is ending.
Let the children go.
They mustn't get trapped here.
Like I was?! Like I was!
(Song starts) You think that I
am happy to be trapped here?
Let me clue you in.
It ain't no breeze.
It might seem rather
fun to be the bad guy.
To be a cad, a fiend.
Do what you please.
To live a life devoted to one's
zaniest desires.
But listen to me, children.
One eventually tires,
Of having what you wish for.
And when the thrill expires,
you're unfulfilled,
Unhappy, ill-at-ease.
You owe me my last wish!
This isn't somewhere made
for the faint hearted.
There's far too much
excitement on this isle.
I had my own volcano,
Buttermoth, and Spider Drone.
They kept me fairly
happy for a while.
You owe me my last wish.
(Spider machine whirs)
Ah! What's going on?!
What have you done?
Fliggle!
(Fliggle noises)
(Spider machine shuts down)
Ah! Ah!
What did you do?!
Ah! Ah! Quit it!
Get off me, you monstrous little
beast! Ah!
(Electricty whirs)
(Spider machine breaks down)
You owe me my last wish!
(Fliggle noises)
(Metallic banging)
Whoa! I'm glad he's with us.
It's him. That silly little man.
(Song resumes)
My beautiful contraption
has been utterly destroyed.
My plans and my machine have
been cast into the void.
It would be an understatement
to say that I'm annoyed.
I used to be so powerful.
Majestic, versatile.
Oh, how I miss my family.
And how I miss my home.
To think that I dismissed them
one and all.
With one more wish
I could've found my
way back to their hearts.
But I am out of wishes.
Feeling small.
And I was wrong to blame The
Wish Collector for my fate.
A little bit too greedy,
didn't think, and couldn't wait.
I've seen the light,
I've seen what's real.
But just a little late.
And I am out of wishes.
Feeling small.
Feeling... small.
Elise, quick!
Wish us home now!
I wish...
I wish that you are set
free from this island.
What?!
(Ding)
Wish granted.
(Music intensifies)
Elise! What have you done?!
You gave up your wish.
I had to. He got trapped on
this island, just like us.
We can't just leave him here.
It wouldn't be right.
I'm me again.
Ha! You saved me.
Ha ha!
(Rock crashes)
(Rocks continue crashing)
Winter's ending.
We have one more wish.
That was our last one.
What?
Long story.
We need to get off
this island now.
(Rocks crashing)
Ahh!
Jump on!
(Honeycomb splashing)
Steady.
Hold on to me tight.
Look out!
(Falling)
Woah!
We're too heavy. The
honeycomb's setting.
Where's The Parrot Ship?
We've completed all our wishes!
The ship was at the dock. We
needed to get back to the dock.
The island is sinking.
We've run out of time.
Oh, no!
Not again!
(Background)
Haha! Woo!
Lad!
Over there! Look over there!
(Music intensifies)
Coming in hot!
Ahoy there!
Hop aboard, me hearties.
I always fancied being a pirate.
You came back for me?
Yeah, of course.
What are friends for?
You didn't think we were gonna
leave you all on your own?
(Laughter)
(Fliggle noises)
I've never had a reason to leave
till now. Maybe we'll meet again
I'll miss you.
Ah! We better get going.
Come on Fligs!
(Fliggle noises)
Woo!
Hehe!
See you later.
(Water bubbling)
Woo! Ha ha woo!
Are the islanders
going to be okay?
Oh, they're all fine. Back
exactly how they want to be.
Ready for another day.
Come on, we need to get home.
Mum must be so worried.
But how do we get home?
Don't we need a
wish to get back?
You don't need wishes.
You never did.
You just needed each other.
Huh.
Now, if you would be so kind as
to pull out my old friend there.
It's a normal watch again!
Nothing is ever
exactly as it seems.
This old timepiece may have
one last trick up its sleeve.
(Ding dong)
(Magic whoosh)
All those wishes,
we just wasted them.
Did we really?
Indeed, Alfie.
Children make wishes every day.
But it's the things you don't
wish for
That are the most important.
What will happen to me?
Well, thanks to Elise here,
you'll be going home too.
But it's been years,
and I'm still a boy.
Time travels differently on The
Land of Sometimes.
For Alfie and Elise they'll be
waking up on Christmas morning.
As for you, you'll be waking up
the morning after the night
you left.
And this will all just
feel like a dream.
(Music intensifies)
Alfie?
Where did all this come from?
About time you two woke up.
Have you been down
here all night?
Did you two do all this?
It's Christmas morning!
He was right!
Who was right? What have you
two been up to?
Are you both okay?
Never been better!
Sorry, mum.
We've been selfish.
And if dad isn't coming
home, we're still a family.
What on earth
happened to you two?
Let's just say it's
been a long, long night.
Well, I hate to admit it, but I
think that all went rather well.
Just the way I planned it.
Codswallop. You didn't
plan any of that.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes I did.
And I think it's time we
got somebody else home.
But there's one more wish.
One more wish remaining.
Well, of course.
I have just the wish.
(Music intensifies)
(Door knocks)
(Door opens)
Father!
You're safe! You're here!
You're such an old softy.
Mind your cogs.
The way to get started is to
quit talking and begin doing.
Time to get you back home.
Ding dong!
All's well that ends well.
(Music intensifies)
I know what you're thinking.
What happened to that kid?
Well, that was me.
Yes. That charismatic postal
worker from the beginning of
the story.
But you knew that.
So if you ever get
a watch in the mail.
(Ding dong)
Be careful what you wish for.
(Laughing)
And remember, yes,
it really is all about me.
Okay Fliggle. Go ahead.
(Music plays)
And you, mischievous fairy,
come on, join in.
(Music continues) You're about
to learn that nothing is the way
You thought it was.
That dark is light.
That dull is bright.
That big is small because
All logic is unreasonable.
No dreary law applies.
No need for things to stay the
same.
No rules for shape or size.
Instead of boring constancy,
a change at every turn.
The everyday mundane routine, no
longer your concern.
A cavalcade of mystery.
A paradox of joy.
Enthralling for a girl like you.
And, I suppose a boy.
Over to you, my
slimy old friend.
Oh, yes, he's squelchy
and quite dear in his way.
It's so fun to make friends.
It's a marvellous day.
He's got scales. He's got swing.
And he's slithery too.
Slithery too.
He's The River Slouch Sling.
Do we like him?
We do.
(Song continues)
Hey, Mrs Blip!
Just don't get goo
over everything.
I'm Mrs Blip and I'm slippery.
I slip and I slide.
I live in a bucket, with bubbles
and slime.
I hide in banana skins.
I had in the tip
And my favourite thing to do,
is make people slip.
Okay, everybody join in.
This is The Land of Sometimes.
The land of now and then.
The now is always with us.
And then comes back again.
The darkest moments lightened.
The happy moments earned.
(Song continues)
This is The Land of Sometimes.
(Music ends)